One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
What?!
‫ماذا؟! هل ستغادر يا أودين-سان؟!‬
There'll be less trouble, but we'll miss him.
‫ستقلّ المصائب، لكنّنا سنفتقده.‬
Hakumai Wano
‫هاكوماي‬ ‫ببلاد وانو‬
I hear a monster lives in Kuri.
‫سمعتُ بوجود وحشٍ يعيشُ في كوري.‬
A demon by the name of Ashura Doji.
‫شيطان يُدعى بأشورا دوجي!‬
Kuri is a cancer in Wano...
‫كوري أشبه بورمٍ أصاب بلاد وانو، حتّى سوكياكي-ساما عجز أمامها.‬
The authorities are powerless to apprehend criminals who take refuge in Kuri.
‫بمجرّد أن يلتجئ مجرم ما إلى كوري، لا تستطيع السّلطات الإمساك به.‬
But they will die there anyway if their strength is lacking.
‫لكنّه ما كان ليستطيع النّجاة في كوري لو لم يكن قويًّا كفايةً.‬
Such a lawless region might as well be another country!
‫مكان لا قانون فيه وبالإمكان عدّه بلدًا مختلفًا بالكامل...‬
Fascinating! I shall tour the land Wano!
‫هذا مثير للاهتمام! سأجول بلاد وانو!‬
Take care!
‫اعتنِ بنفسك!‬
Kin! Denjiro!
‫كين! دنجيرو!‬
Come visit us again!
‫زورونا ثانيةً!‬
See you!
‫إلى اللّقاء!‬
He comes and goes as he pleases.
‫يأتي ويذهب كما يحلو له.‬
He is a free spirit.
‫إنّه حرّ تمامًا...‬
Lord Yasuie!
‫ياسويي-ساما!‬
We have a problem!
‫ثمّة مصيبة!‬
Look at the state of his accommodations!
‫انظر للغرفة الّتي مكث فيها! ما الّذي فعل بها لتصل لهذه الحالة؟!‬
We must charge him for the repairs!
‫علينا أن نجعله يدفع مقابل الإصلاحات!‬
Or we just pretend we were struck by a natural disaster...
‫حسنٌ، لنتظاهر أنّ كارثة طبيعيّة حلّت بنا فحسب...‬
My lord, you are too soft on him!
‫أنت متساهل معه كثيرًا!‬
Lord Yasuie!
‫ياسويي-ساما!‬
What now?
‫ماذا هنالك أيضًا؟‬
There is money missing?
‫اختفى المال؟‬
Yes, and I am certain it was locked in the safe!
‫نعم! كان في الخزنة بكلّ تأكيد!‬
Um...
‫عفوًا...‬
It pains me to say this...
‫أكره قول هذا...‬
but I witnessed the whole thing!
‫لكنّني رأيته!‬
Um... Lord Oden...
‫عفوًا، وضع أودين-ساما المال في جيب صدره الدّاخليّ...‬
I knew he did it!
‫إنه هو كما اعتقدت! عضّ اليد الّتي أطعمته!‬
This is unforgivable!
‫هذا لا يُغتفر!‬
I think Oden would have taken it openly.
‫أعتقد أنّ أودين لن يُخفي حقيقة أخذه له.‬
Are you sure, Orochi?
‫أأنت واثق يا أوروتشي؟‬
Y-Yes! My apologies!
‫نعم، اعذرني!‬
I was so scared that I couldn't stop him!
‫كنتُ خائفًا وعجزتُ عن فعل أيّ شيء!‬
After leaving Hakumai, Oden's group continued to cause trouble throughout Wano
‫بعد مغادرة مجموعة أودين لهاكوماي، واصلوا التّسبب بالمصائب في أنحاء بلاد وانو...‬
as they headed toward Kuri.
‫وهم في طريقهم إلى كوري!‬
How long are you two going to follow me?!
‫إلى أين ستواصلان اللّحاق بي؟!‬
Forever!
‫لأي مكان!‬
We love you so much!
‫إنّنا نحبّك كثيرًا!‬
– He looks annoyed!
‫يبدو مُنزعجًا.‬
Hey! Why are you standing out there?
‫أنتما! لماذا تقفان هناك؟!‬
As your retainers, we must stand guard.
‫نحن تابعاك ولذلك نحرسك!‬
Come in, you idiots!
‫ادخلا أيّها الغبيّان!‬
– Oden!
‫أودين-سان!‬
What are you doing?
‫ماذا تفعل؟‬
I'm keeping a logbook.
‫أكتب يوميّاتي.‬
Apparently, voyagers overseas write in them every day on their ships.
‫سمعتُ أنّ الملّاحين خارج البلاد يكتبونها كلّ يوم على سُفنهم.‬
The following are Oden's own words regarding his journeys.
‫الكلمات التّالية هي ما كتبه أودين في يوميّاته عن رحلته.‬
Ringo
‫رينغو‬
In Ringo, we came across a couple of starving brothers in rags.
‫في رينغو، قابلنا أخوين رثّي الملابس ويتضوّران جوعًا.‬
Izo Son of a Former Hanayanagi Dance School Headmaster
‫إيزو‬ ‫ابن معلّم رقص‬ ‫هاناياناغي سابق‬
Kikunojo Izo's Younger Brother
‫كيكونوجو‬ ‫أخو إيزو الصغير‬
Get lost!
‫ارحلا!‬
They were trying to earn money by dancing, but people were cold.
‫كانا يحاولان جني المال بالرّقص، لكنّ النّاس عاملوهما ببرود.‬
Why are you two following me?!
‫لماذا أنتما تتبعانني أيضًا؟!‬
Stop eating, you brats!
‫كفّا عن الأكل أيّها الشّقيّان!‬
I want more.
‫أريد المزيد.‬
I said stop!
‫قلت توقّف!‬
Do not give him any more!
‫لا تعطه المزيد!‬
They mentioned being the heirs to a school of dance,
‫قيل إنّهما كانا ابنَيْ معلّم رقص،‬
but their father was arrested, breaking up their family.
‫لكنّ والدهما اعتُقل وتشتّتت عائلتهما.‬
They brazenly ate our oden, sobbing all the while.
‫لقد أكلا الأودين خاصّتنا بكلّ وقاحة وهما يبكيان.‬
Kibi
‫كيبي‬
In Kibi, there was a ghoul who collected hair from the living and dead alike.
‫في كيبي، كان هنالك غول يقصّ شعر الأحياء والأموات أيضًا ويأخذه.‬
He was a freak who made a living selling brushes made from the hair.
‫كان منحرفًا يصنع فُرَشًا ويبيعها لجني قوت يومه.‬
Kanjuro Ghoul of Kibi
‫كنجورو‬ ‫غول كيبي‬
Whoa! I give up! I give up! I give up! I thought you were a corpse!
‫مهلًا! أستسلم! أستسلم! أستسلم! ظننتُك جثةً!‬
I punched him for coming after my hair, but then he began to follow me too.
‫سعى خلف شعري ولكمته، لكنّه تبعني بعدها.‬
He claimed to have suffered— and deservedly so—from persecution.
‫ادّعى أنّه عانى من الاضطهاد في الماضي رغم أنّه كان يستحقّه.‬
Udon
‫أودون‬
In the forest-covered Udon, there were rumors of a notorious mountain bandit.
‫وفي أودون ذات الغابات الكثيفة، تحدّث النّاس عن قاطع طرق الجبال المشهور.‬
They said women would be abducted, and men would be beaten soundly.
‫قيل إنّ النّساء تُختطفن والرّجال يُضربون بشدّة.‬
Why are you all following me?!
‫لماذا تتبعونني؟!‬
You're telling me!
‫أليس كذلك؟‬
Is that the mountain bandit?!
‫هل ذاك هو قاطع طرق الجبال المُشاع عنه؟!‬
Lord Oden!
‫أودين-ساما!‬
Raizo Former Member of the Kozuki Clan's Oniwabanshu
‫رايزو‬ ‫عضو سابق من‬ ‫أونيابانشو عشيرة الكوزكي‬
The prodigious ninja, Raizo, quit the Kozuki Clan's Oniwabanshu after a kunoichi broke his heart.
‫ترك أونيابانشو عشيرة الكوزكي بعد أن فطرت كونويتشي قلبه، إنه النينجا العبقري رايزو‬
I cannot live my life in hiding any longer!
‫ما عدتُ أريد أن أعيش حياتي في الخفاء!‬
He looks annoyed...
‫يبدو مُنزعجًا!‬
Lawless Land of Kuri
‫أرض كوري الخارجة عن القانون‬
Ashura Doji Strongest Monster in Kuri
‫أشورا دوجي‬ ‫أقوى وحش في كوري‬
Kozuki Oden has come to Kuri?
‫أتى كوزكي أودين إلى كوري؟‬
He's the shogun's son!
‫ابن الشّوغن إذًا...‬
I wanna kill him myself!
‫أريد قتله بنفسي! اقبضوا عليه وأحضروه إليّ!‬
– Yes, sir!
‫حاضر!‬
Those in power... We hate them most of all!
‫أصحاب السّلطة... هم أكثر من نكره!‬
Where's Oden?
‫أين ذهب أودين-سان؟‬
He went south of here to take a dump.
‫ذهب جنوبًا لقضاء حاجته.‬
Wasn't that yesterday?
‫ألم يكُن ذلك البارحة؟‬
He sometimes disappears on a whim for one or two days, right?
‫ألا يختفي حضرته أحيانًا عندما يحلو له ليوم أو يومين؟‬
Hey, Raizo! There's a gate to Kuri in the south!
‫يا رايزو! مدخل كوري في الجنوب!‬
What?!
‫ماذا؟!‬
Crap! I swore I'd die for him, and now I'm late to join him on the battlefield!
‫تبًّا! كنتُ عازمًا على الموت من أجله، لكنّني تركته يذهب لساحة القتال وحده!‬
Kuri
‫كوري‬
This was a place filled with the stench of death, blood, and violence!
‫امتلأ ذلك المكان برائحة الموت والدّماء والعنف!‬
It was like a different world.
‫كان أشبه بعالم مختلف، كانت تنتابهم جميعًا رغبة بقتلي.‬
I'll lop off your head, Kozuki Oden!
‫سأقطع رأسك يا كوزكي أودين!‬
Open up the borderless map, then
‫استهل قراءة الخريطة التي لا حدود لها‬
Head for that unknown edge of the ocean
‫انطلق نحو المكان الذي لا نهاية له‬
LET’S SAIL ON right now, hoist your sails up high
‫لنبحر للأمام ونرفع تلك الأشرعة‬
Riding on the wind
‫الحق بالرياح‬
DON’T GIVE UP, it’s time to finish what we started
‫لا تستسلم ما دمت عازمًا‬
So don't you grow disheartened
‫فلا عودة للوراء‬
Laugh the tears away through the storm
‫سنواجه المياه المتقلبة بضحكاتنا‬
SHOUT IT OUT, when you feel down always remember
‫اصرخ لحماية عزيمتك من الانكسار‬
That’s what your friends are there for
‫فرفاقك يقفون إلى جانبك‬
Y’know there’s no point in fronting,
‫ليس عليك التظاهر بالقوة أبدًا‬
Even in the face of utter darkness
‫ولو حاولت الظلمة أن تنال من صميمك‬
C’mon, BRAVE IT OUT We’ll be alright
‫هيا، تشجع‬
Together you know that we’ll never lose a fight
‫فالروابط الثابتة باقية‬
Open up the borderless map, then
‫استهل قراءة الخريطة التي لا حدود لها‬
Head for that unknown edge of the ocean
‫انطلق نحو المكان الذي لا نهاية له‬
All great journeys starts with a single step
‫كن جسورًا لتخطو خطوة للأمام‬
DREAMIN’ ON
‫تمسّك بالحُلم‬
Open up the borderless map, then
‫استهل قراءة الخريطة التي لا حدود لها‬
Raise the flag we swore to defend
‫تلك الراية برهان على نذرنا‬
We’ll never stop until we’ve reached the top
‫تواصل النضال‬
Just be true to yourself until the end
‫فابقَ مخلصًا لجوهرك‬
Set sail and grab it, DREAMIN ON
‫تمسك بالحلم وداوم عليه‬
Daimyo and Retainers
‫الدايميو وخدمه‬
You're Kozuki Oden, huh?
‫أنتَ كوزكي أودين إذًا‬
I have been disowned,
‫ما عاد لي اسم الآن بعد التبرؤ مني!‬
You can enter all you like, but we kill any who try to leave!
‫بإمكان الجميع الدّخول، ولكن من يحاول الخروج يُقتل‬
Especially samurai!
‫وخاصّة السّاموراي!‬
It is so restrictive!
‫إن المكان مشبع بالقيود!‬
How can anyone live in a place like this?!
‫أنّى لأحدٍ العيش هنا؟!‬
That's hilarious.
‫هذا مثير للضّحك.‬
You're never going to leave this place!
‫لن تتمكّن أبدًا من الخروج من هنا!‬
No, don't even try to leave!
‫ولا تفكّر حتّى في محاولة الخروج!‬
"Don't even try to leave"?
‫«ولا أحاول الخروج»؟‬
That is my least favorite rule!
‫هذه أكثر قاعدة أكرهها!‬
I make the rules here!
‫أنا من يسنّ القواعد هنا!‬
Cut him down!
‫اقطعوه!‬
That makes you the boss?
‫هل أنت الزّعيم؟!‬
– Oden!
‫أودين-سان!‬
Look! The gate has been broken!
‫انظروا! حُطّمت البوّابة!‬
How can an ass who grew up pampered in the capital...
‫أنتم الحمقى الّذين عاشوا في رغد العاصمة...‬
understand what it's like to live in hell?!
‫لا يمكنكم أبدًا فهم مشاعر من عاش في الجحيم!‬
Is that all you really want to say?!
‫أهذا ما تريد قوله؟!‬
Look!
‫انظروا هناك!‬
Up there!
‫هناك في الأعلى!‬
Oden! We're here to back you up!
‫أودين-سان!‬
I must apologize.
‫المعذرة.‬
I seem to have finished up already.
‫أنهيت الأمر برمّته توًّا.‬
It took me an entire day and night.
‫تطلّب الأمر منّي اليوم بطوله، وليلته أيضًا.‬
Kill me already!
‫اقتلني فحسب!‬
I know what the future holds anyway.
‫أعلم ما يخفيه المستقبل في كلّ الأحوال.‬
I've got nothing to live for!
‫لستُ نادمًا على أيّ شيء!‬
This is the infamous Ashura Doji?!
‫أهذا أشورا دوجي شائن السّمعة؟!‬
Hey, you guys!
‫يا رفاق!‬
Do you still love me?
‫أما زلتم تحبّونني؟‬
Lend me your wisdom and strength!
‫ساعدوني بحكمتكم وقوّتكم!‬
I have decided that the worthless scum here...
‫قرّرت أن أقف على رأس هؤلاء الحثالة العاجزين...‬
need me as their king!
‫ملكًا لهم!‬
Flower Capital
‫عاصمة‬ ‫الزهور‬
My lord, Shogun! Lord Oden is at it again!
‫أيّها الشّوغن-ساما! إنّه أودين-ساما ثانية!‬
What? What did he do this time?!
‫ماذا؟ ماذا فعل هذه المرّة؟!‬
Look at this!
‫انظر لهذا!‬
That lawless Kuri...
‫كوري الخارجة عن القانون...‬
Only he could do this...
‫وحده القادر على هذا...‬
Is this all true?
‫أكُلّ ما ذُكِر هنا صحيح؟‬
Leading the roughnecks of the bloody and hellish land of Kuri,
‫سخّر أودين بعد قيادته لصعاليك الأرض الجحيميّة والدّمويّة كوري،‬
Oden utilized their abundant energy to turn the wild land into a habitable place.
‫طاقتهم الوفيرة وحوّل الأرض الجامحة إلى مكان صالح للعيش.‬
After hearing of this accomplishment, Shogun Kozuki Sukiyaki revoked his disownment
‫وردّةَ فعلٍ لهذا الإنجاز، سحب الشّوغن كوزكي سوكياكي قرار التّبرّؤ،‬
and bestowed upon his son the title of daimyo of Kuri.
‫ونصّب ابنه دايميو لكوري.‬
Reformation of Kuri
‫إصلاح‬ ‫كوري‬
Our great Lord Oden will become the daimyo of Kuri!
‫سيصبح قائدنا أودين-ساما العظيم دايميو كوري!‬
Hooray!
‫مرحى!‬
Then it'll become a full-fledged province!
‫بهذا ستصبح كوري إقليمًا كاملًا بمعنى الكلمة!‬
Reformation of Kuri
‫إصلاح‬ ‫كوري‬
I can't believe it! But we stuck it out to the end!
‫لا أصدّق هذا! لكنّنا تمسّكنا بالأمر حتّى النّهاية أيضًا!‬
Reformation of Kuri
‫إصلاح‬ ‫كوري‬
Kin...
‫كين-تشان...‬
You did it! Our beloved Oden did it!
‫تهانينا يا عزيزنا أودين-سان!‬
Hooray!
‫مرحى!‬
You're amazing, Oden!
‫أنت مذهل يا أودين-سان!‬
You're finally Kuri's–
‫وأخيرًا أصبحت على كوري...‬
Oden!
‫أودين!‬
Absolutely!
‫هذا صحيح!‬
Daimyo!
‫دايميو!‬
– Lord Oden!
‫أودين-ساما!‬
What is the matter, Ashura?
‫ما الخطب يا أشورا؟‬
I...
‫أنا...‬
have never seen peace before.
‫لم أشهد سلامًا من قبل.‬
Thank you, Oden!
‫شكرًا لك يا أودين!‬
Stop it! You are creeping me out!
‫توقّف! أنت تثير اشمئزازي!‬
You bastard!
‫أيّها الوغد!‬
What're you doing?! Stop it!
‫ماذا تفعل؟! توقّف!‬
Hey!
‫تمهّل!‬
I said "Stop it"!
‫قلتُ «توقّف!»‬
Screw you!
‫سُحقًا لك!‬
Knock it off already!
‫كفّ عن هذا حالًا!‬
Now, a daimyo requires retainers.
‫إنّ الدّايميو بحاجة لخدمٍ الآن.‬
Instead of surrounding myself with the usual wise and sober men...
‫بدل أن يُعيّنوا لي خدمًا حُكماء وفطنين،‬
I would rather have you all.
‫أريدكم دون سواكم.‬
Be my samurai!
‫كونوا السّاموراي خاصّتي!‬
– Lord Oden!
‫أودين-ساما!‬
S-S-Stop it!
‫تـ-تـ-توقّفوا! أنوفكم تسيل! إنّها تسيل! لقد وقعت عليّ!‬
Stop it!
‫توقّفوا!‬
Six years after that moment in time... yet thirty-three years before the present day...
‫ثمّ، بعد 6 سنوات... قبل 33 سنة من الوقت الحاضر،‬
across the world, disbanded members of the legendary Rocks Pirates
‫بعيدًا في مكان ما من العالم، شكّل بقايا قراصنة الروكس الأسطوريّين المنحلّين...‬
each formed a new crew, extended their influence, and became infamous.
‫طواقم جديدة ووسّعوا نفوذهم وذاع صيتهم.‬
Kuri Beach Wano
‫شاطئ كوري‬ ‫بوانو‬
What are they? Animals?
‫ماذا يكونون؟ حيوانات؟‬
Hairy humans?
‫أم رجال كثيري الشعر؟‬
Deformed monsters?
‫وحوش غريبة المظهر؟‬
Did you get it?
‫أنلتَ منه؟‬
Yeah...
‫نعم...‬
In the distant past, many centuries ago,
‫في الماضي قبل مئات السّنين،‬
we minks and the samurai of Wano's Kozuki Clan
‫عقدنا نحن قبيلة لعشيرة وساموراي الكوزكي من بلاد وانو...‬
made a pledge to become sworn brothers.
‫عهدًا وأقسمنا بأن نكون حلفاء.‬
Damn! Wano is the worst!
‫تبًّا! بلاد وانو هي الأسوأ!‬
Dammit! Let me down!
‫سُحقًا! أنزلوني!‬
I'm a kappa!
‫أنا كابّا!‬
Which makes you a monster!
‫إذًا فأنت وحش!‬
I wish we'd never set sail!
‫أتمنّى لو لم نبحر بتاتًا!‬
I wish we hadn't come here!
‫أتمنّى لو لم نأتِ إلى هنا!‬
This isn't how you treat brothers!
‫سُحقًا لقسم التّحالف ذاك!‬
A cat monster, dog monster, and a kappa...
‫وحش قطّ ووحش كلب وكابّا...‬
Is this beach cursed?
‫أهذا الشّاطئ ملعون؟ لنحرقهم أحياء!‬
Don't do it!
‫إيّاكم!‬
That is plenty of ingredients for today's oden...
‫بهذه، لديّ مكوّنات تكفي لتحضير أودين اليوم...‬
You wretches!
‫أيّها الأوغاد!‬
You should all be ashamed!
‫عار عليكم أيّها الأوغاد!‬
Beef Tendon
‫أوتار‬ ‫بقر‬
You fear what is different out of ignorance!
‫إنّكم تخشون من يختلفون عنكم بسبب جهلكم!‬
It is pathetic to torment such little creatures!
‫كيف سوّلت لكم أنفسكم تعذيب هؤلاء الصّغار؟!‬
Thank you...
‫شكرًا لك...‬
Farewell.
‫حسنٌ...‬
– Don't leave us like this!
‫لا تتركنا هكذا!‬
So, who are the monsters?
‫من هؤلاء المخلوقات الصّغيرة؟‬
They followed me.
‫إنّهم تبعونني.‬
Inuarashi Mink
‫إينواراشي‬ ‫من المينك‬
Thank you for saving us!
‫شكرًا على إنقاذنا!‬
It's hot!
‫هذا ساخن!‬
Between starvation, a shipwreck, and a violent mob, we almost died!
‫كاد العنف يقتلنا إضافة لجوعنا وتحطّم سفينتنا!‬
Neko- mamushi Mink
‫نيكوماموشي‬ ‫من المينك‬
Ouch!
‫هذا ساخن!‬
Hey! This is too hot to eat!
‫مهلًا! هذا ساخن ولا يمكنني أكله!‬
Whoa...
‫مهلًا... لا يمكنني الاعتياد على رؤية حيوانات تتكلّم.‬
The minks!
‫عشيرة المينك! أخبرني والدي عنهم سابقًا.‬
I thought so!
‫ذلك ما توقّعته! لدينا ذلك الرّمز في بلادنا أيضًا!‬
You-gara and our people are brothers!
‫أنتم-غارا ونحن إخوة!‬
And you saved our lives!
‫وقد أنقذت حياتنا! كنّا نتضوّر جوعًا...‬
I see...
‫فهمت... كلوا بقدر ما تشاؤون.‬
Here's to our savior.
‫شكرًا لك يا منقذنا!‬
Ouch!
‫هذا ساخن!‬
Don't be shy.
‫لا تخجل. سيعجبك الفجل.‬
I won't forget this favor.
‫لن أنسى هذا المعروف أبدًا.‬
Hot!
‫هذا ساخن!‬
Try the hanpen.
‫تناول بعض الهانبن.‬
The konnyaku–
‫كونياكو...‬
No! It's too hot to eat!
‫كلّا! هذا ساخن جدًّا ليُؤكل!‬
My tongue is sensitive like a cat's!
‫لديّ لسان حسّاس!‬
Bad cat!
‫أيها القط الشرير!‬
Hey! Wait, Cat!
‫مهلًا، توقف يا قط!‬
Hey, Cat!
‫يا قط!‬
Oden was meant...
‫لا يُسمى الأودين أودين...‬
to boil!
‫ما لم يكن يغلي!‬
– That's kinda cool!
‫هذا رائع!‬
Tastes good to me.
‫إنّه لذيذ بالنّسبة لي.‬
And what are you?!
‫من أنت؟!‬
The ship my mother and I were on sank, and...
‫غرقت السّفينة الّتي كنّا عليها، وأنا وأمّي قد...‬
we were cast ashore in this country.
‫جرفنا البحر إلى هذه البلاد.‬
We asked for help, but people threw rocks at us for being fishmen.
‫طلبنا المساعدة، لكنّ النّاس ألقوا الحجارة علينا لأنّنا كنّا برمائيّين.‬
My mother got hurt, so we couldn't go back to where we came from.
‫تأذّت أمّي، لذلك لم نستطع العودة لموطننا.‬
Before my mother died, she told me,
‫أخبرتني أمّي قبل أن تموت:‬
"Fishmen suffer discrimination...
‫يعاني البرمائيّون من التّمييز،»‬
so claim that you're a kappa."
‫لذلك تظاهر أنّك كابّا.»‬
I'm Kawamatsu the Kappa.
‫أنا كاواماتسو الكابّا. وكنتُ أعيش على مخلّفات الطّعام.‬
Kawamatsu "the Kappa"
‫كاواماتسو‬ ‫كابّا‬
Thank you for saving me and treating me to such a delicious meal.
‫شكرًا على إنقاذي وتقديم وجبة لذيذة كهذه لي.‬
I'll never forget this.
‫لن أنسى معروفك أبدًا.‬
May I eat the rest?
‫أيمكنني أكل كلّ شيء؟‬
Nonesense. We'll cook more, so just wait a bit.
‫لا عليك، سنطبخ واحدًا جديدًا، لذلك انتظره.‬
No, that's not necessary. It's still edible.
‫لا، هذه مضيعة فما زال صالحًا للأكل.‬
Oh no...
‫كلّا. أسأت التّصرّف وأهدرت الطّعام.‬
You've grown up.
‫لقد نضجت من ذلك.‬
I'm meowwy sorry, Kappa!
‫اعذرني-نيا أيّها الكابّا!‬
I'll eat it, too!
‫سآكله أيضًا!‬
It's still too hot!
‫ما زال ساخنًا جدًّا!‬
What an amusing cat!
‫يا لك من قطّ مضحك!‬
Cat!
‫يا قط!‬
There must still be creatures out there I've never seen before.
‫ما زال هنالك مخلوقات لم أرها من قبل هناك.‬
Meeting you all has reinvigorated my desire to one day set sail!
‫بعد رؤيتي لكم، ما عدت أطيق الانتظار حتّى أبحر يومًا.‬
Sounds great!
‫ممتاز!‬
The world's a big place!
‫هذا العالم واسع!‬
Well then, take care!
‫حسنًا. إلى حال سبيلكم!‬
Let us stay here!
‫دعنا نمكث هنا!‬
Were you listening to us?!
‫أكنتَ تصغي إلينا؟!‬
We have no place to go!
‫لا مكان لدينا لنقصده!‬
All right! All right!
‫حسنًا! حسنًا!‬
Yay!
‫مرحى! مرحى!‬
We got more people...
‫ازداد عددنا ثانيةً‬
I guess you just can't reject anyone.
‫أعتقد أنّه لا يمكنك ردّ أيّ أحد...‬
That's fine and all, but we're in a bind here.
‫لا بأس بذلك، لكنّنا في ضيقة.‬
You lent money to Orochi without asking me again!
‫أعرت المال لأوروتشي دون أن تسألني مرّة أخرى! لماذا قد تُعِر المال لحثالةٍ مثله؟‬
You see...
‫حسنٌ...‬
He may be independent now, but with his ties to Yasuie, I cannot abandon him.
‫قد يكون مستقلًا بنفسه الآن، ولكنه كان من رجال ياسو-سان سابقًا، لا يمكن أن أتركه‬
Silent steps. Stealthy steps. Ninja steps.
‫بلا صوت، على رؤوس الأصابع، وبكلّ سرّيّة.‬
Understood? These are the fundamentals.
‫فهمتم؟ هذه هي الأساسيّات.‬
– Okay!
‫نعم!‬
Let's go!
‫لننطلق! لا تخافوا من ياسويي!‬
Hakumai
‫هاكوماي‬
Silent steps. Stealthy steps. Ninja steps.
‫بلا صوت، على رؤوس الأصابع، وبكلّ سرّيّة.‬
Why would you want to steal this much money?
‫لماذا حاولتم سرقة كلّ هذا المال؟!‬
Lord Oden was broke!
‫أودين-سان بورطة وهو بحاجةٍ للمال!‬
If you're gonna kill us, just do it already, you hedgehog!
‫إن كنت تريد قتلنا، فافعل ذلك أيّها القنفذ!‬
If it'll help Lord Oden...
‫إن كان ذلك سيساعد أودين-سان...‬
I'm happy to die!
‫فلن أموتُ نادمًا‬
Damn you, Oden. You certainly know how to pick them.
‫أودين الوغد... جمع حوله أشخاصًا غريبين...‬
I am giving you the money you tried to steal.
‫بإمكانكم أخذ المال الذي حاولتم سرقته!‬
– What?!
‫ماذا؟!‬
Lord Yasuie! These are Hakumai's funds!
‫ياسويي-ساما! ماذا عن مصاريف هاكوماي؟!‬
And...?
‫وأيضًا...‬
You can have this too. It is yours!
‫استعملوا هذا المال، إنّه من نصيبكم!‬
Even more money?!
‫مزيد من المال؟ أنت تخدعنا، أتحاول إيقاعنا في فخ؟‬
Do you love Oden?
‫أتحبّون أودين؟‬
Then take this money, make yourselves presentable, learn some manners, buy some books, and study!
‫إذًا، استعملوا هذا المال لتحسّنوا من حالكم وتتعلّموا آداب التصرف واشتروا كتبًا وثقّفوا أنفسكم!‬
These don't suit us!
‫إنها لا تناسبنا!‬
I am...
‫أنا...‬
No! Speak from your stomach!
‫كلاّ! تحدّث من بطنك!‬
- Religion - History - Economics - Samurai - Etiquette mDtq08'ZH kicV5673M B!R0OkG2k RV;l1es4X 7qE,wk"3u Jo1bbGZ.W Suw.r.:qz R8'j202em kxx02jUvX IOJxR:Kcu UET.RSAtC jqBdNsERE
mDtq08'ZH kicV5673M B!R0OkG2k RV;l1es4X 7qE,wk"3u Jo1bbGZ.W Suw.r.:qz R8'j202em kxx02jUvX IOJxR:Kcu UET.RSAtC jqBdNsERE
Having a bunch of lowlife retainers like you would only disgrace Oden!
‫الآداب السّاموراي الاقتصاد التّاريخ الدّين‬
Lord Oden, would you kindly elaborate on your temperament this fine morning?
‫هلاّ تكرّمت علينا وأخبرتنا بحالك اليوم يا أودين-ساما‬
This ganmodoki is exquisite!
‫إنّ هذا الغانمودوكي فاخر للغاية!‬
What is the matter with you all?! You are all creeping me out!
‫ما خبطكم يا رفاق؟ إنّكم مريبون جدًّا هذه الأيّام!‬
He is the man who will one day become the shogun of Wano!
‫سيصير شوغن بلاد وانو يومًا.‬
Those who serve him ought to be the best samurai Wano has to offer!
‫إنّ على من يدعمونه أن يكونوا أفضل السّاموراي في بلاد وانو!‬
Of course, protecting your lord is a must.
‫وعليكم حماية سيّدكم طبعًا!‬
The capital city...
‫وصيروا الملائكة الحارسة للعاصمة...‬
No, the entire country of Wano will have you as its guardians!
‫بل لبلاد وانو يومًا!‬
Three Years Later Thirty Years Before the Present Day
‫بعد ثلاث سنوات‬ ‫قبل 30 سنة من الوقت الحاضر‬
Flower Capital
‫عاصمة‬ ‫الزهور‬
I hear the daimyo of Kuri and his court are coming to the capital.
‫ستحضر مجموعة دايميو كوري إلى العاصمة.‬
Make sure you don't get robbed.
‫احذروا أن تُسرقوا.‬
Lord Oden's retainers are known thugs.
‫خدم أودين-ساما مجرّد صعاليك‬
Look! They're here!
‫انظر! لقد وصلوا!‬
What?!
‫ماذا؟!‬
Oh, my! Look at those samurai!
‫مهلًا! ما الّذي حلّ بأولئك السّاموراي؟!‬
Were Lord Oden's retainers always so dignified?
‫أكان خدم أودين-ساما رائعين هكذا دائمًا؟!‬
I hardly recognized them!
‫كلّا، لقد تغيّروا!‬
It's like a shogun's procession!
‫هذا أشبه بموكب الشّوغن!‬
The regal postures of those samurai were so glorious that some people even forgot to breathe.
‫كانت هيئاتُ أولئك السّاموراي الفخمةِ مهيبةً لدرجة أنّ البعض نسوا التقاط أنفاسهم.‬
And one could have seen people drop to their knees everywhere in the capital.
‫وهناك من رأى أنّ رُكب النّاس قد خارت في كلّ العاصمة.‬
Hey, Father!
‫مرحبًا يا والدي!‬
Oden!
‫أودين! أصبحت رجلًا عظيمًا! فوجئ الجميع!‬
I have only been made into a fine man.
‫جعلوا منّي رجلًا عظيمًا فحسب لكنّني لم أتغيّر بتاتًا.‬
M-M-My Oden feels grateful toward others?!
‫لا-لا-لا أصدّق أنّك تشعر بالامتنان للآخرين!‬
Why should that scare you?
‫لا داعي للخوف!‬
Hearing of his father's illness, Oden rushed to the capital and was relieved to see him in good health.
‫بعد سماعه لمرض والده، أتى أودين مسرعًا للعاصمة وارتاح لرؤيته في أفضل حال.‬
However, this would be the last time they ever exchanged words.
‫ولكن هذه آخر مرة يتحدثان فيها لبعضهما بعضًا.‬
It seems this place is inhabited.
‫أشعر بوجود أحدٍ يعيش هنا.‬
Pops, it'll take a week to repair it.
‫يا والدي، سيتطلّب منّا إصلاحها أسبوعًا.‬
The water damaged most of the cargo!
‫معظم الحمولة متضرّرة من الماء!‬
The Same Year... Itachi Port Kuri
‫نفس السّنة‬ ‫«ميناء إيتاتشي»‬ ‫كوري‬
We need to procure supplies.
‫نحن بحاجة للحصول على طعام ومؤن.‬
Who wants to go?!
‫من يريد الذّهاب؟!‬
Almost everyone since we all need some exercise.
‫جميعنا تقريبًا بما أنّنا بحاجة لبعض التّمرين.‬
Captain Edward Newgate Whitebeard Pirates
‫القبطان إدوارد نيوغيت‬ ‫قراصنة اللحية البيضاء‬
We climbed up the falls, right?
‫تسلّقنا الشّلاّلات، صحيح؟‬
Why is there sea and an island here?
‫فلماذا هنالك بحر وجزيرة هنا؟‬
We have a problem, Sir Kanjuro!
‫لدينا مصيبة يا كنجورو-دونو!‬
What is it?
‫ما الخطب؟‬
Calm yourself! You are too loud!
‫اهدأ، صوتك مرتفع جدًّا!‬
We received a report that a pirate ship docked at Itachi Port!
‫وصلنا بلاغ بأنّ سفينة قراصنة رست في ميناء إيتاتشي!‬
Pirates?!
‫قراصنة؟!‬
Lord Oden!
‫أودين-ساما! إلى أين تمضي؟!‬
To the port!
‫إلى الميناء!‬
Here I go! Here I go!
‫هيّا! هيّا!‬
Alright, we'll go fetch some supplies.
‫حسنًا، سنذهب لإحضار الطّعام والمؤن!‬
I'm coming, too!
‫سآتي أيضًا!‬
You can't.
‫لا يمكنك. أنت مجرّد متدرّب!‬
Don't say that!
‫لا تقولي ذلك!‬
Pops! Can I go?
‫يا والدي! أيمكنني الذّهاب؟!‬
Do as you like.
‫افعل ما يحلو لك.‬
All right! Let's go!
‫حسنًا! لننطلق!‬
Hurry up! Hurry up!
‫بسرعة! بسرعة!‬
I said no apprentices allowed!
‫قلتُ لا يسمح للمتدرّبين بالمجيء! ابق هنا!‬
What?!
‫ماذا؟! ذهب أودين-ساما إلى الميناء؟!‬
Why did you let him go?!
‫لماذا سمحت له بالذّهاب؟!‬
I heard there's a pirate ship at Itachi Port!
‫سمعتُ أنّه توجد سفينة قراصنة في ميناء إيتاتشي!‬
It's unusual, too!
‫وهي لا تشبه السُفُن المعتادة أيضًا!‬
They say it's big and the pirates look tough!
‫قِيلَ إنّها كبيرة وقراصنتها أشدّاء!‬
We must stop him!
‫علينا إيقافه!‬
He just went to chase them away, right?!
‫ألم يذهب لطرد القراصنةِ فحسب؟‬
Not likely!
‫لا تتغابَ! أنا واثق أنّك على دراية...‬
Lord Oden's dream!
‫بحلم أودين-ساما!‬
Is that a pirate ship?!
‫أهذه هي؟! سفينة قراصنة؟!‬
I have been waiting...
‫انتظرتُ...‬
for this moment!
‫هذه اللّحظة طويلًا!‬
Here comes trouble.
‫نحن في ورطة!‬
Hey, all of you! Stand back!
‫تراجعوا يا رجال!‬
Something's coming!
‫ثمّة شيء قادم!‬
Something unthinkable!
‫شيء غير عاديّ بالمرّة!‬
Well done!
‫مرحبًا!‬
You made it past the terrible weather and waterfalls! Quite impressive!
‫أنا جدّ سعيد لتمكّنكم من الوصول إلى هنا رغم الجوّ السّيّئ والشّلاّلات!‬
I have been waiting for you, pirates!
‫كنتُ في انتظاركم أيها القراصنة!‬
You are really something else!
‫أيّها العجوز! أنت مذهل!‬
I'll make you pay for that!
‫سأجعله يدفع الثّمن!‬
Bring it on, you punk!
‫أرني ما لديك أيّها الشّقيّ!‬
I have been waiting for someone like you!
‫كنتُ في انتظار رجلٍ مثلك!‬
My name is Kozuki Oden!
‫اسمي كوزكي أودين!‬
I do not know who you are, but please allow me...
‫لا أعرف من تكون، لكن اسمح لي...‬
to ride on your ship!
‫بالإبحار على سفينتك!‬